Matthew Sadecki

Phone: 647-996-4586 | Email: matthewsadecki@gmail.com | Github: github.com/sadecki558 LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/matthew-sadecki | Website: www.matthewsadecki.com

SUMMARY

Multidisciplinary full stack web developer with a background in applied economics and data analytics. I hold a certificate in full stack web development from University of Toronto and have experience working with machine learning and building web apps. I enjoy learning about and creating new technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, Javascript, Java, C, C#

Technologies: Git, Node, React, React-Native, MySQL (SQL), MongoDB (NoSQL)

Web & Design: HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, Media Queries, APIs, AJAX, Express.js, Balsamiq Data Analytics: Knime, Tableau, Machine Learning, Python Libraries: Pandas, Scikit-learn, Seaborne

EXPERIENCE

Mobile Application Developer Intern, HSB BI&I

May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Machine Learning Project | Tech Stack: Python Libraries: pandas, scikit-learn, and seaborne
 - Selected Kaggle datasets to challenge qualified candidates at IT recruiting event
 - Performed ETL processing on datasets, explored correlations, ran machine learning algorithms, created data visualizations, and created summarized analysis in documents
 - Managed and prioritized multiple concurrent cross-departmental tasks in preparation for recruiting event, and presented complex technical information to non-technical staff
- Progressive Web App Project | Tech Stack: Ionic, React Native, Microsoft Power Apps
 - Developed proof-of-concept apps using popular frameworks to test the viability of required features and presented findings to IT team using matrix style comparisons
 - Performed unit testing on a mobile inspection app used by equipment inspectors

Business Owner, Ivespark Solutions

May 2018 - Present

- Tutoring | gradementor.com | Tech Stack: Wordpress, CSS, PHP
 - Tutored K-12 and University students in Math, Physics, and Computer Science
- Web Development | getmoreclients.ca | Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, Node.js, Express.js
 - Met with clients to gather requirements, outline schedules, and present wireframes
 - Deployed mobile responsive and seo optimized websites onto linux servers using PuTTY

Tutor, Medlife Queen's

Sept 2016 - April 2018

• Prepared students for calculus and physics exams in a lecture hall by taking up past exams

PROJECTS

LeadGen | github.com/sadecki558/leadgen | Tech Stack: React-Native, MySQL, FireBase, Socket.io

• LeadGen is a cross platform mobile application that is intended to help users find and chat with potential contractors. LeadGen is a functioning React-Native chat application with live chat.

Telco Customer Churn | <u>matthewsadecki.com/data/report.pdf</u> | **Tech Stack:** *Knime, Python*

- Cleaned and standardized Telco customer data using python script
- Explored correlations, ran machine learning and data clustering algorithms using Knime to help understand and predict customer behaviour with the goal of retaining customers

EDUCATION

B.A. (Honours): Applied Economics, Queen's University

Sept 2015 - April 2020

• Relevant Coursework: Econometrics, Data Analytics, Data Structures, Java, Python, C, Financial Risk Management, Cost-Benefit Analysis, Statistics, Labour Economics, Health Care Economics

Full Stack Web Development, University of Toronto

May 2018 - Nov 2018

- Built frontend and backend of websites (MySQL/MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js)
- Worked in a team to develop apps while applying version control and issue tracking (Kanban)